<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//Samba-Team//DTD DocBook V4.2-Based Variant V1.0//EN" "http://www.samba.org/samba/DTD/samba-doc">
<refentry id="libsmbclient.7">

<refmeta>
	<refentrytitle>libsmbclient</refentrytitle>
	<manvolnum>7</manvolnum>
</refmeta>


<refnamediv>
	<refname>libsmbclient</refname>
	<refpurpose>ネットワークブラウザのための拡張ライブラリであり、一般的なブラウジングの API を実装する。</refpurpose>
</refnamediv>

<refsynopsisdiv>
	<cmdsynopsis>
		<command>Browser URL:</command>
	<para>
        smb://[[[domain:]user[:password@]]server[/share[/path[/file]]]] [?options]
    </para>
	</cmdsynopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>


<refsect1>
	<title>解説</title>

	<para>
	このツールは <citerefentry><refentrytitle>samba</refentrytitle>
	<manvolnum>7</manvolnum></citerefentry> スイートの一部である。
	</para>

	<para>
	<command>libsmbclient</command>は、ローカルなUNIX/Linuxファイルを操作するために有効なたくさんの標準POSIX関数を使う
        CIFS/SMBネットワークリソースを操作するためのアプリケーションを許可するライブラリツールセットである。これは、ブラウズ、
         ファイルのオープン/クローズ、読み書き、アクセス権変更、ファイルの時刻変更、属性とACLの操作やその他などを許可する。もちろん、
         この機能は一般的にブラウジングと呼ばれる機能のすべてを含む。
	</para>

	<para>
	<command>libsmbclient</command> は、コマンド行からは直接使えないが、その代わりに、ファイルマネージャとブラウザのような
        ツールの機能の拡張を提供する。このマニュアルページにはそのツールのための構成方法を説明するので、ユーザーはとても優れた機能を
        持つユーティリティを得ることができる。
	</para>
</refsect1>

<refsect1>
	<title>オプション</title>

	<para>
	URLの意味は以下のとおり:
	</para>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>smb://</term>
			<listitem><para>
			ネットワーク中で有効なすべてのワークグループかドメインを表示する。動作はマイクロソフトのWindows
			エクスプローラと一致する。
			</para>

			<para>
			The method of locating the list of workgroups (domains also) varies depending on the setting of
			the context variable <literal>(context-&gt;options.browse_max_lmb_count)</literal>. It is the
			responsibility of the application that calls this library to set this to a sensible value.  This
			is a compile-time option. This value determines the maximum number of local master browsers to
			query for the list of workgroups.  In order to ensure that the list is complete for those present
			on the network, all master browsers must be querried. If there are a large number of workgroups
			on the network, the time spent querying will be significant. For small networks (just a few
			workgroups), it is suggested to set this value to 0, instructing libsmbclient to query all local
			master browsers. In an environment that has many workgroups a more reasonable setting may be around 3.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>

		<varlistentry>
			<term>smb://name/</term>
			<listitem><para>
			This command causes libsmbclient to perform a name look-up. If the NAME&lt;1D&gt; or
			NAME&lt;1B&gt; exists (workgroup name), libsmbclient will list all servers in the
			workgroup (or domain). Otherwise, a name look-up for the NAME&lt;20&gt; (machine name)
			will be performed, and the list of shared resources on the server will be displayed.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>

	<para>
	When libsmbclient is invoked by an application it searches for a directory called
	<filename>.smb</filename> in the $HOME directory that is specified in the users shell
	environment. It then searches for a file called <filename>smb.conf</filename> which,
	if present, will fully over-ride the system <filename>/etc/samba/smb.conf</filename> file. If
	instead libsmbclient finds a file called <filename>~/.smb/smb.conf.append</filename>,
	it will read the system <filename>/etc/samba/smb.conf</filename> and then append the
	contents of the <filename>~/.smb/smb.conf.append</filename> to it.
	</para>

	<para>
	<command>libsmbclient</command> は、 <literal>USER</literal>パラメータのためにユーザのシェル環境をチェックし、
                   もしも<literal>user</literal>パラメータがURLに含まれていないならば、その値を使う。
	</para>

</refsect1>

<refsect1>
	<title>プログラマーズガイド</title>

	<para>
	招来の更新のためにこの場所をウォッチして欲しい。
	</para>

</refsect1>

<refsect1>
	<title>バージョン</title>

	<para>
	このマニュアルページはSamba3.0スイートのために修正された。
	</para>
</refsect1>

<refsect1>
	<title>作者</title>
	
	<para>オリジナルの Samba ソフトウェアと関連するユーティリティは、Andrew
      Tridgell によって作られた。Samba は現在、Linux カーネルが開発されているような方法でのオープンソースプロジェクトである Samba Team によって開発されている。</para>

	<para>
	libsmbclient のマニュアルページは John H Terpstra によって書かれた。
	</para>
</refsect1>
<refsect1>
	<title>日本語訳</title>
	<para>このマニュアルページは Samba 3.2.4  対応のものである。</para>

	<para>Samba 3.0.23 - Samba 3.0.24 対応の翻訳は、たかはしもとのぶ (monyo@samba.gr.jp) によって行なわれた。</para>
	<para>Samba 3.2.4 対応の翻訳は、太田俊哉 (ribbon@samba.gr.jp) によって行なわれた。</para>
</refsect1>

</refentry>
